海德高中
重返17岁
1989年的麦克・奥唐奈
奥唐奈  留点劲儿比赛
O'donnell, save something for the game.
我在热身  教练
I'm just warming up, coach.
刚刚又和球探谈了  他今晚来
Just talked to the Scout again. He's coming tonight.
你打满半场  我知道你行
You play half the game. I know you're capable of.
他打算提供给你全额奖学金
He's prepared to offer you a full scholarship.
大学的免费直通车  孩子  你的前途很光明
Free ride to college and the world's your oyster, kid.
谢谢  教练
Thanks, coach.
好啦  队员们  集合  合影
All right, jockstraps, let's gather up. Picture time.
都给我上镜点
Try not to break the camera.
等会儿  内德还没来
We gotta hang on. Ned's not here yet.
管他的  他不过是送水的
Who cares    He's the water boy.
这无所谓  但他是队里的一员
That doesn't matter, because he's part of the team.
对不起  我迟到了
Sorry I'm late   Sorry I'm late
如果我在和怪兽的大战中
But what kind of dungeon master would I be
中途开溜
if I left my party in the middle
我算哪门子的地下城主
of a battle with a hippogriff
瞧瞧  女孩版的麦林(亚瑟王中的魔法师）
Check it out, it's Merlin in the girlin.
内德  我是你最好的朋友
Um, Ned, Ned, look, I'm your best friend, all right,
我一直站在你这边
And I'll always have your back.
但当你穿着袍子出现时
But there's only so much I can do
我只有一件事能做
when you show up in a dress.
奥唐奈  你和小乔治
O'donnell. How about you and boy George
该归队了吧
join us for this picture
是的  当然  稍等
Yep. Yep.   Just one sec.
请把牌子给那个小子  好啦
Give the little guy the sign, please. Here we are.
很好  后面的往前一点
Nice, guys. Scoot up in back.
你们得把最帅的一面
Come on, you gotta look pretty
展现给那些女孩子们  对吧
for the ladies, right    Come on.
很好  开拍了  3  2  1
Yeah. let's do it. Three, two, one.
喂  香草冰(著名歌手）
Hey, vanilla ice.
我们还要比赛  让我们开场吧
We got a game here. Let's bring it in.
伙计  我是被逼的  我是被逼的
Man, I had to. I had to.
伙计  瞧那边
Oh, man, over there.
那个冷冰冰的狐狸精是谁
Who is that stonecold fox
是我女朋友
Oh, it's my girlfriend.
把他们一网打尽  老兄
Take no prisoners, bro.
我的女孩来啦
Oh, hey, there's my girl.
我真高兴你来了  斯嘉
I'm glad you're here, Scar.
球探要来  搞得我超紧张
This whole Scout thing has me wicked nervous.
我觉得我的未来就指望这场比赛了
I just feel like my whole future's riding on this game.
是啊  我明白你的感受
Yeah. yeah, I know how you feel.
真的  一切 一切都好吗
Yeah    Is everything     Everything's cool, right
是啊  一切都好极了
Oh, yeah. Everything's totally copacetic.
都好  都好
Totally      Totally.
奥唐奈
O'donnell.
我得上场了  回见
I gotta go. See you.
你还好吧
You okay
我们可以赛后再谈  不  就现在
We can talk about it later.   No. Just tell me.
今晚对你很重要  你该尽情享受
It's your big night. Go enjoy it.
除非你告诉我怎么了否则我无法享受它
I can't enjoy it unless you tell me what's going on.
好吧
Okay.
奥唐奈
O'donnell
清醒点
Wake up
奥唐奈
O'donnell
你在干嘛
What are you doing
斯嘉  等等
Scar   Scar, hey.
斯嘉丽
Hey, Scarlet.
喂  你在干什么
Hey, hey. Hey, what are you doing
麦克  你在干什么
Mike, what are you doing
听着  你和我  我们一起面对这件事  好不好
Look, you and me, we're in this together, okay
但是这场比赛  是你的未来
But the game. That's your future.
不  这个婴儿才是我的未来
No, the baby's my future.
你疯了  你是我的未来
That's crazy.   You're my future.
我不能让你抛弃这一切  我不会让你这么做
I can't let you throw this all away. I won't let you.
如今的麦克・奥唐奈
谢谢你让我住这  内德
Thank you for letting me stay here, Ned.
不客气  没什么
Oh, yeah. No problem.
你吃的惯麦片吗  吃的惯  很好
You good on the cap'n      I'm good on the captain.
麦克
Hey, Mike
麦克  我知道你很沮丧  但是有点你得相信我
Mike, I can tell you're down, but trust me on this.
你在等斯嘉丽
You're looking at Scarlet
把你踢出家门
kicking you out of the house
而事实上孩子们
And the kids wanting nothing
不愿和你在一起  这也是不利因素
to do with you as a negative, when in fact
我猜大多都对你不利  是啊
I guess it's mostly negative, isn't it      Well, yeah.
我想不出有利的
I had no upside for that.
今天是你升职的大日子对吧
Hey   You're getting that big promotion today, right
是的  是的
Yes. Yes, I am.
今天是我转运的一天
Today everything turns around for me.
给他们好看
Knock them dead.
我爱你
I love you
所以不管怎样
So anyway
公司让我们拖延时间
the way corporate wants us to spin it
这种方式   可能就像在某些情况下
is that maybe, in certain situations
四小时的持续勃起并没那么糟
a fourhour erection isn't such a terrible thing.
好了  下一件事
OK. Next staff.
正如绝大多数人所知  今天我将荣幸
As most of you know,today I am proud
任命我们的新地区销售主管
to be naming our new Regional Sales Manager.
来吧
Here we go.
我已经在制药业这行里
You know I've been in the pharmaceutical game
打拼了近两年了
for almost two years now
人们总是问我
And people always ask me
如何成为地区销售主管
What's it take to be an RSM
领导力
Leadership.
勇气
Courage.
正直
Integrity.
但最重要的是  对公司的无私奉献
But most importantly, dedication to this company.
所以恭喜  麦克
So congratulations. Mike.
麦克  如果你能往左靠一靠
Mike, if you could slide to your left
我就可以恭喜我们的新地区销售主管了
so I can congratulate our new RSM,
温蒂
Wendy
天啊  天啊
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
出去庆贺吧  女士们
Go out there and push some pills, my peeps.
干得好  宝贝
Good job, baby
再见  谢谢
Byebye, thanks.
看你的表现
See you at practice.
麦克  怎么有事吗  兄弟
Mike. What's crackalacking, coz
我来告诉你怎么了
Well, I'll tell you what's crackalacking.
你耍我吧
Are you kidding me
温蒂在这干了2个月  我已经干了16年了
Wendy's been here two months. I've been here 16 years.
我是组里干得时间最长的
I got the best numbers on the team.
你可以把这看作对你的赞赏
You should think of it as a compliment.
就像我们说
Think of it as us saying,
升职已无法体现你的价值
You're just too valuable to promote.
你这个小
You little
你好  老兄  不  不  不  我有时间
Hey, buddy. No, no, no, I got time.
我知道  听着
I know, right    Look, listen,
他是我的双
she was my doubles par
这么多人   就一个提升名额
So many girls and only one promotion,
没人嫉妒  你们太支持我了
Nobody get jealous. But you guys are so supportive.
温蒂  这是你应得的  谢谢
But, Wendy, you did it.   Thank you.
温蒂  温蒂
Wendy   Wendy   Wendy
服了你们了  天啊
You guys   Omg.
还有好戏呢
Oh, and it gets better,
因为我们要去星期五狂欢
because we are going to t.g.i. friday's
不是吧
Shut up
麦克・奥唐奈
Mike O'donnell.
我认识你吗
Do I know you
不  但我认识你
No. But I know you.
是吗
Oh, yeah
高中明星
High school star.
潜力无限
Never quite lived up to your potential.
迟早你会回到这所学校
Sooner or later you all come back to the old school.
站在这  凝望过去那些辉煌日子的照片
Stand there and look at the picture of the glory days
猜想原本会是什么样子
wondering what might have been.
在我看来  你们都活在过去
Seems to me you guys are living in the past.
我当然想回到过去
Well, of course I want to live in the past.
那的生活更好
It was better there.
我打赌你想重来一次
I'll bet you wish you had it to do all over again.
你说中了
You got that right.
你确定
You're sure about that
确定
Oh, yeah.
老爸  你好  奥唐奈先生
Dad.   Hi, Mr.O'donnell.
小姐们好啊  你在这干嘛
Ladies.   What are you doing here
我刚刚在和
Oh, I was just talking to
没什么
nobody.
别管了
Doesn't matter.
我今天下班早
I got off work early,
我想我们可以一起去吃冰激凌
and I thought we could get ice cream.
一起
Together
为什么  叫上你弟弟  好吧
Why      Just go get your brother, okay
还需要别的吗
Do you need anything else
不了  谢谢
No, we're fine.
怎么了  你们以前最喜欢这了
What's the matter    This used to be your favorite place.
我们曾来这给你过生日
We used to come here for your birthday.
没错  那时我才8岁
Yeah. When I was, like, 8.
艾尔  篮球赛季就要来了
So, Al, basketball season's coming up.
你准备好了  是的
You ready      Yeah.
在练习外线投篮吗
Been working on that outside shot
传球  很好
Passing      Good.
运球  很好
Dribbling      Really good.
只是好没法让你拿到奖学金
Good's not going to get you a scholarship.
我是说  好极了  好极了  老爸  非常好
I meant, it's great. It's great, Dad. It's great.
不愧是我儿子  记住  不在于你的身材有多壮
That's my boy. Remember, it's not how big you are.
而在于比赛中如何最大限度发挥你的作用
It's how big you play.
来
Right up here.
玛姬被乔治敦大学录取了
Maggie got into Georgetown.
玛姬  太棒了
Maggie, that's awesome.
你能把这调小点声吗
Can you turn down the
好的  孩子们  回见
Okay, guys, see you soon.
我爱你们  很高兴和你们聊天
Love you. Nice chatting with you.
你在干嘛
What the hell are you doing
那是我的
Hey, that's my stuff.
你干嘛毁了我们的院子
Why are you destroying our yard
这不是我们的院子  是我的  记得吗
It's not our yard. It's my yard, remember
你选了马路  所以院子归我了
You took the road not taken. And I get the yard.
我要把它变成给我客户的示范地
I'm going to turn it into a showpiece for my clients.
什么客户  园艺设计
Clients of what      Landscape design.
园艺设计
Landscape design
我要向人们展示我能做的
I'm going to show people what I can do.
好吧  但是离婚
Yeah, well, the divorce isn't final
两周后才生效
for another two weeks,
所以你还没权利
So you do have no right.
是吗  过去18年我一直在
Really    So I've spent the last 18 years
听你抱怨说如果不是我的话
of my life listening to you whine about the things
你能做什么  你却说我没权利
you could've done without me, and I have no right
只是  我花了很多心血在这
It's just I put a lot of work into this yard.
是吗
Did you
是吗  比如那个烤肉专用坑
Really    Like the barbeque pit
是的
Yeah.
根据我的记忆
The way I remember that is that
你曾花一个小时弄好它
you spent about an hour working on it
却在接下来两天里
and then you spent the next two days
抱怨说如果你上了大学
complaining about if you had gone to college,
你就可以雇个人做
you could've hired someone to do it.
没两天吧
I don't think it was a whole two days.
那边的吊床呢
Or the hammock over here.
怎么了
Yeah.
我想你之所以放弃那个
I think you quit that one
是因为你已决定不再尝试
because you just decided not to try anymore.
试着站在我的立场看待这一切
Look, try to see things from my point of view.
我对我的人生失望透顶
I am extremely disappointed with my life.
我从没要求你娶我
I never asked you to marry me.
没有  但我这么做了
Yeah, but I did.
那今后你不用再帮我什么了
You don't have to do me any more favors, then.
我们也不会再去挽回对方了
We're not going to hold each other back anymore, okay
斯嘉  我们法庭上见  听审时
Scar    I'll see you at court, okay    At the trial.
斯嘉丽
Scarlet.
内奥蜜
Naomi
你来了  当然我会来
You came.  Of course I came.
如果我不在你离婚时陪伴你
What bridesmaid would I be
我还算什么伴娘
if I didn't hold your hand during the divorce
现在  记住  第一次总是最难的
Now, just remember. The first one's always the hardest.
麦克  奈奥蜜
Mike.   Naomi.
是内奥蜜  管你叫什么
Naomi.   I don't care.
我们走  我们得让你做好准备
Let's get going. We got to get you ready.
重回这行
Back on the market.
没错  我很在行
Yeah, I'm a real catch.
单身母亲带着两个十几岁的孩子
Single mom with two teenage kids
却不得不去摆弄肥料
and manure caked under my fingernails.
你能行的  你能把12岁的男孩搞上床
You'll do great. You got the butt of a 12yearold boy.
好极了  希望我们的女儿能听到
That's terrific. I hope our daughter heard that.
你多久没做爱了
When was the last time you waxed
再见  麦克
Bye, Mike.
再见
Bye.
你确定吗
You're sure about that
上帝
Jesus.
快下来
Hey   Get off of there
不  能听到吗
Oh, No. Hello
听到了吗  听到了吗
Hello      Hello
那是
What the
不要啊
Oh, no
天啊
Oh, man.
内德
Ned
小偷
Thief
不  不  内德  不  不  是我
No, no, no, Ned   Ned, no, no, no   It's me
住手  住手
Stop   Stop
内德
Ned
感觉好极了
Oh, wow. I feel great.
你想干嘛  别啊  内德
What are you doing    No, Ned.
不要
No.
不  不  不  内德
No, no, no, Ned
内德  拜托  是我  我是麦克
Ned   Come on   It's me, it's Mike
内德  听我说  听我说
Ned, Ned，I'm telling you, I'm telling you
住手 马上给我住手
Stop it  Stop it   Now
一把优雅的武器
An elegant weapon
来自一个更为文明的时代
from a more civilized time.
是我  我是麦克・奥唐奈  你最好的朋友
Hey, it's me   It's Mike O'donnell, your best friend
你有隐睾
You have an undescended testicle.
谷歌上能查到
Googleable
内德
Ned
数学考试时你帮我作弊  但我被抓住了
You helped me cheat on my math test, but I got caught.
公共记录上有
Public record
你邀请莱亚公主参加中学舞会
You asked princess Leia to junior prom.
地区新闻上报道了
Covered by the local news.
我喘不过气来了  我喘不过气来了
I can't breathe   I can't breathe
拜托
Please.
上帝啊
Oh, my god.
不  不  不要
No, no, no.
内德  内德
Ned, Ned.
天啊
Oh, my god.
你能别盯着我看吗
Would you stop staring at me
你把我吓坏了  这把我吓坏了
It's freaking me out.   It's freaking me out
我回到少年时期了
I'm pubescent
好吧  那么
Okay. So, uh
这是个经典的变身故事
it's a classic transformation story.
在文学作品里无数次出现
It appears in the literature time and time again.
你曾被伽玛射线射中过吗
Were you at any point shot by a gamma ray
没有  接触过某种伽玛射线
No.   Exposed to gamma radiation of any kind
没有 内德  没有
No, Ned.   No
有你也看不到 好吧
You wouldn't see it. Okay.
那就减少了很多可能性
That eliminates these and those and most of that side.
你现在或者曾经变成过一个
Are you now or have you ever been
挪威神 吸血鬼或是时光穿梭生化人吗
a Norse God, vampire, or timetraveling cyborg
我们什么时候认识的  一年级
I've known you since, what, first grade
如果有的话我早告诉你了
Maybe I would have told you.
吸血鬼不会说的  生化人自己不会知道
Vampire wouldn't tell. Cyborg wouldn't know.
闭嘴
Shut up.
好吧  如果不属于这些情况
Okay, if it's not any of those,
我猜  我们得瞧瞧你基本的
I guess, um, we're looking at your basic
灵媒变身魔术
spirit guide transformation magic.
事实这可算个大问题
That's kind of a biggie, actually.
找到了
That is here.
当英雄
When the hero
我猜这指的是 我猜是你
I guess that's  I guess, you.
被他的灵媒变身
uh, is transformed by his spirit guide
并重新安排他的人生
to set him on a new path.
什么意思  我看起来像你的灵魂向导吗
Which is what      Do I look like your spirit guide
那个清洁工
The janitor.
清洁工
你们看到清洁工了吗  你们看到清洁工了吗
You guys seen the janitor    You seen the janitor
你知道清洁工在哪吗  不知道
Do you know where the janitor is      No.
清洁工在哪  他在哪工作
Hey, where's the janitor    Where does the janitor work
抱歉  你没事吧  孩子
Excuse me     You all right, kid
这的另一个清洁工  就我一个
There's another janitor who works here.   Just me.
不  不  这还有一个
No, no. There's an older guy
白发的老头也在这工作
with white hair who works here.
我昨天还在这和他谈话
I was here yesterday talking to the janit
我给他看了我的这张照片
I showed him this picture of me.
你的照片  是的
You      Yeah.
那张照片是1989年拍的
That picture's from 1989.
是啊  算了
Right. Forget it.
阿莱克斯
Alex
阿莱克斯  老兄
Alex, buddy
阿莱克斯
Alex
有人在吗
Hello
灵媒  是你吗
Spirit guide
我该怎么办
What am I supposed to do
我不知道该怎么办
Don't know what I'm supposed to do.
我被打中了  我被打中了吗 有个兵被干掉了
I got shot. Did I get shot or did I get     Someone got powned.
是个手榴弹  内德
It's a grenade.  Ned.
什么  唉  年轻版的你
Aah   Oh, sorry. Teenage you.
我想明白了  我知道该怎么做了
I figured it out. I figured out what I'm supposed to do.
我知道灵媒要我做什么了
I figured out what my spirit guide wants me to do.
我要回去
I'm going back.
我要重回高中
I'm going back to high school, Ned
不不  这不可能
No   No, no. No way.
你的灵媒不会将变形的魔法浪费在
Your spirit guide would not waste transformation magic
让你重回高中和做返校节国王上  不可能
On you reliving your senior year and going to prom. No.
内德  这是我重塑人生的机会  让一切变好
Ned, this is my chance to have my life over, but to do it right.
换作是你  也会这么做吧  不会
Wouldn't you, if you had the chance     No.
我很富有  今天没人找我麻烦
I'm rich, and nobody stuck my head in a toilet today.
是吗  再说这也不光是为了我自己
Sure. Besides, it's not just about me.
是为了你  不  远不只是为了我
It's about you.  No, it's much bigger than me.
就是为了你  好吧  或许是为了我
It's about you.  Okay, maybe it's about me
但那又有什么错
But what's wrong with that
1989年以后我就没为自己活过
I have not done anything for me since 1989.
你爱怎么着都行
You do what you have to do.
但是别让我和你一起趟这浑水
But don't think about sucking me into this with you.
海顿高中是我人生的低谷
Hayden was the low point of my existence
我发誓绝对不会再回到那鬼地方
And I vowed I would never go back to that godforsaken place
绝不  从不
Never, ever, ever
永不  绝不  从不  永不
Never   Never, ever, ever
我恨你
I hate you.
您好
Hello.
我来为儿子
I'm here to enroll my son
办入学手续
In school.
他叫马克
Mark.
您好啊
What's up
那么
So
我们先坐下等您一会儿
So we'll just have a seat till you're ready for us.
我们马上 好吧
We'll be right, uh  okay.
你穿的像什么样子
What's this you're wearing
很酷  嬉皮士风格
This is cool. This is hip.
凯文・费德林也有过相似的打扮
I have a picture of Kevin Federline wearing the same thing.
我不认得  你穿的什么
I don't know who that is.  What are you wearing
你穿的像个老爹  我本来就是
I told you, like a dad.  I am.
你看起来像克莱・艾肯  别提他了
You look like Clay Aiken.  Leave him out of this.
你确定这些不会穿帮吗  当然不会  我是谁啊
Are you sure these look legit     Oh, yeah. Look who you're talking to.
我发明了软件
I'm the guy who invented the software
防止人们窃取音乐
That prevents people from stealing music.
我还发明了帮助人们窃取音乐
I also invented the software that helps people steal music
但那只是个美妙的插曲
But that's a happy coincidence.
那是什么
What is that
我的天啊
Oh, my g
拿错了  那些是我的  你开什么玩笑
Wrong. These are for me.  You kidding
她叫什么名和奇威是我的
What'shername and Chewie's for me.
可以去见马斯特森小姐了
Miss Masterson will see you now.
走吧
Let's go.
不要闹笑话
Just don't try to be funny, all right
少说少错
Say as little as possible.
看路  土包子
Hey, watch where you're going, toolbag.
很抱歉  是我们不好  斯坦
So sorry, sir. Our fault.  Stan.
你好  我是简・马斯特森  海顿高中校长
Hello. I'm Jane Masterson, principal here at Hayden High.
你好
Hi.
Hello.
你好  你好
Hello.  Hi.
可以了
Uh, okay.
可以松手了
Yeah, I think we're good here.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们刚才的握手产生了爱的结晶
I think our hands just made a baby.
请原谅我父亲
Excuse my dad.
他不太喜欢和迷人的女士交谈
he's not used to talking to attractive women.
谢谢你的
Oh, thank you
我叫马克  马克
Mark.  Mark
谢谢你那不合时宜的恭维
For that flattering yet totally inappropriate comment.
请坐
Please sit.
谈话开始前  我想告诉您  马克是个杂种
Before we get started, I think you should know that, uh, Mark's a bastard.
什么
Excuse me
他是非婚生子  也就是说
I had him out of wedlock, so
我是单身
I'm single.
钻石王老五
And I'm very rich.
好吧
Okay.
你带来成绩单了吗  是的
Did you bring your transcripts     Oh, yeah.
成绩单
Transcripts.
你之前在康涅狄格州的卡特勒高中
Last school you went to was Cutler High in Connecticut.
是优等生  真不错
StraightA student. Very impressive.
数学俱乐部
Math club
全国资优成绩总决赛
National Merit Finalist
科尼岛吃热狗比赛冠军
Coney Island hot dog eating champion.
海顿高中有幸请你入学
Well, I think Hayden would be lucky to have you.
欢迎  谢谢
Welcome.  Thank you.
高德先生  您还有什么问题
Uh, yes, Mr. Gold. Do you have a question
你的头发很美
Your hair is pretty.
虽然不是个问题  不过谢谢你
Ah. Not a question, but thank you.
我可以嗅一下你秀发的味道吗
Would the lady mind if I smelled it
我想该跟你说明白
Now is probably a good time to tell
我们不准和学生家长约会
You that I don't date students' parents.
我也该向你申明
Maybe I should tell you that I never
我和所有我孩子的校长都约过会
Don't not date the principal of my child.
好了  爸爸  好啦
Okay, come on, dad. Come on, dad.
走吧
Let's go.
就快说完了
I was about to close
你想表现好吗  那就沉着点  你是个父亲
You have to do it right now    Just calm down. You're a dad.
天啊  我们置身其中了
Hi. oh, my gosh. we're in.
看见她那赤裸裸的眼神没
You see her undress me with her eyes
我可不这么想
I don't think that's what that was.
真不敢相信我们做到了
Hey. wow. I don't know how we did it.
那是玛姬的朋友  看着
It's Maggie's friends. Watch this.
姑娘们  怎么样  你是谁啊
Hey, girls, how's it going      Do I know you
当你自己是谁  明星么
What'd you do, mug kfed
欢迎来到金字塔底部
Welcome to the bottom of the food chain.
在高中永远有我支持你
Hey, look, you always had my back in high school, okay
如果你的灵媒要你假扮青少年
So if your spirit guide wants you to be a fake teenager
我愿意做你的假老爸
And me to be your fake dad
至少我能保证自己的假儿子看上去
The least I can do is make sure that my fake son doesn't look
不那么傻气
Like a total douche.
我才不傻  真是个傻冒儿
I don't look like a douche.   What a douche.
我们去采购
We're going shopping.
真的  没错  你的上衣让人看了眼晕
Really     Yes, your shirt is bedazzled.
是宝石晃眼
Bedazzled with rhinestones.
去上学吧
Let's go to school.
快看呐  老兄
Hey, yo, check it out.
真嚣张
That's just rude.
你看什么
What's up, dude
你乱看什么  小阿飞
What are you looking at, punk
看着点  醒醒吧  傻子
Watch it.  Wake up, douche.
抱歉
Sorry.
别打电话  别发短信
No phones, no texting.
坐好  大家都坐好
Settle, people. Settle down.
禁止在教室打闹
Take the roughhousing outside, class.
你好
Hello
你好  你到底在哪儿
Hello     Where the hell are you
我的天
Oh, cr
是那件事  你是说我们的离婚
The thing.   You mean our divorce
你到底有没有认真对待这事儿
Do you take any of this seriously
没有  不  我很认真
No, no   Yes, I take this seriously.
我突然需要出国
I had to leave the country very suddenly, uh
去和玛雅人和印加人
With the Mayan  Inca,
我现在秘鲁和印加人在一起
I'm with the Incas in Peru.
我想我们能找到新的
We think we might have found the next
生发剂
rogaine.
你和一个女孩在一起
Are you with a girl
没有  只不过是一群啦啦队员
No, no. It's, uh, a bunch of cheerleaders.
你能和10年级生约会吗
So would you consider maybe dating a 10thgrader
我认为抚养权可以完全归你
I think we could go for full custody.
不  你不能把孩子夺走
No, you can't take my kids away from me.
你何时开始关心了
Since when do you care
听着
Look
我和他们的距离  远比你想像的要近
I'm a lot closer to them than you think.
我们再谈  好吗
Let's reschedule, okay
玛姬
Hey, Maggie.
为什么这个新生朝我挥手
Um, why is the new kid waving at me
我不知道
I don't know.
如果这男孩是苹果的话
But if that boy were an apple
味道一定不错
He'd be a delicious.
天啊
Oh, god.
天  我们身材都很棒
Gosh, we are all in such great shape.
知道吗  跟你透露个秘密
Man, you know, I will tell you something.
再过10年  我们就该有啤酒肚了
In 10 years you're going to have this thing right here
做多少仰卧起坐都减不下去
That no amount of crunches will get rid of.
局部瘦身   全是胡说
And spot reduction, total lie.
我
You know, I
别介意  把球给我
Never mind. Give me the ball.
假动作向右  实际向左
Fakes right, goes left.
经典上篮
And signature move.
孩子
Kid.
我是墨菲教练
I'm coach Murphy.
你还没退休  什么
You're still here     What
你是个传奇人物
You're a legend.
是啊  不过是二十年前
Yeah. Well, yeah. Twenty years.
这是我带的最后一届了
It's actually my last one.
跳跃力很好  控球不错
Good hops, kid. nice handle.
我们需要一个得分后卫
We're looking for a point guard.
是吗
Oh, yeah
为什么不来试试  好的
Why don't you come to tryouts     Okay.
我说完了  好的
I'm done talking to you.  yeah, yeah.
进展如何
Hey, how's it going
一起顺利
Things are looking up.
墨菲教练邀我入队
Coach Murphy practically put me on the team.
这不是个巧合  一切都在步入正轨
That's not a coincidence. We're on the path.
很好
That's great.
你正找回自己的命运  等等等等
That's super you're finding your destiny and, blah, blah, whatever.
有件事情  我需要你帮忙
Here's something. I need you to do something for me.
我需要你惹点事
I need you to get in trouble.
不要犯大事
Not, like, big trouble.
只要惹的麻烦足够让校长请家长就行
Just enough trouble so that the principal needs to meet with your father.
好吧  再说吧
Yeah, okay, well, we'll see.
内德  赢了
Oh   boom. Ned
萨米尔  将死
Boom. Checkmate, Samir
见鬼  将死
Damn it     Checkmate.
能帮我个忙吗
Uh, can I get a little help in here
阿莱克斯
Alex
怎么会
How does it
是谁干的  篮球队的人
Who did this to you     The basketball team.
为什么  你是他们的队友啊
But why    Why    You're one of them.
你人缘很好
You're popular.
这是私事  我又不认识你
Uh, look, this is kind of personal, and I don't know you.
我被粘在厕所上了  是啊
I'm taped to the toilet.  Yeah.
我是马克・高德
I'm sorry, I'm Mark Gold, uh,
是你内德叔叔的儿子  我刚刚转来
your uncle Ned's kid. I just started here.
不错  很好
Oh, cool. Cool, yeah.
我很想和你握手
Well, I'd shake your hand
但手被粘在屁股上了  没关系
But it's taped to my ass.  Right. right.
能帮个忙吗
Would you mind
当然  当然  谢谢
Yeah, yeah, sure.  Yeah, um.
撕开就行  我来撕
Just rip.  I'm going to get it.
是胶布  撕吧
Bandaid.  Go for it.
为什么我们从未谋面
So how come we never met
我妈不想让人知道我是内德的私生子
My mom didn't want anyone to know she had a kid with Ned.
这倒是  是啊
That makes sense.  Yeah.
我们就像家人一样
So since we're practically family and all
爸爸说我们应该互相照顾  你说呢
My dad says we should just keep an eye on each other, you know
当然  为什么不呢
Uh, yeah. Why not
下次你可以在他们把我绑在马桶之前救我
Next time you could get there before they tape me to the toilet.
没错
You got it.
看上去很美味
This looks good.
那是谁
Who's that
妮可  你们两个要约会
Nicole.  Are you two going out
不  不  她是啦啦队长
No, no, she's the, uh, head cheerleader.
她不会和我约会的
She'd never go out with me.
我第一次见到你妈妈的时候  很是紧张
You know, when I first met your mother, I was so nervous
你见过我妈妈
You met my mother
什么  我妈妈
What     My mother.
你说你第一次见到我妈的时候很紧张
You said,       the first time I met your mother, I was nervous.
真是奇怪  你妈妈很火辣吗  老兄
Oh, that's weird. is your mom hot     Dude, what
要我怎么回答  我只是在开玩笑
What do I say to that     I was joking. joking, dude.
斯坦
Stan.
我讨厌那人
I hate that guy.
天  多谢
Oh.  Thanks.
想怎样
What
新生  三明治不错
Freshman. Good sandwich.
就是那个人把你绑在马桶上吗
Is that the guy who taped you to the toilet
没错
Yeah.
昨天他在我家把我塞进了洗衣机
Yesterday he shoved me in a washing machine in my own house.
那混蛋在你家干什么  他是玛姬的男朋友
What was that jerk doing at your house     It's Maggie's boyfriend.
玛姬居然有个男朋友
Maggie has a boyfriend
我对你姐姐很失望
I'm very disappointed in your sister.
他在看你  别看着他  他脾气暴躁
He's looking. Don't make eye contact. He's kind of temperamental.
你在看他  别看了  别看了  就是要看他
You're looking. stop it, stop it.  I'll look at him.
这不是发光的傻冒儿吗
Hey, twinkle douche.
早知道你在食堂就该把你和煮饭婆绑一起
If I wanted you in the cafeteria, I would've taped you to a lunch lady.
你这个小阿飞
You little punk.
别这么跟他说话
You don't talk to him that way.
怎么
Yeah
你能怎么样
What are you gonna do
我能怎么样
What am I gonna do
首先
First
我要向你父亲告状
I'm going to call your father.
我警告你
Heads up
把球给我  贱人
Give me my ball back, bitch.
斯坦  我真为你感到悲哀
You know, Stan, I feel sorry for you.
你不认识我  我真的认识
You don't know me.  Oh, but I do.
生活中一切完美
All too well.
你就是这种人
You're the man.
篮球队队长
Captain of the basketball team.
和漂亮女孩约会
Dates the pretty girls.
高中就像是你的王国
High school is your kingdom.
但是  大家注意
But, people
斯坦不过是个恶霸
Stan's a bully.
为什么呢
Why
斯坦专门欺负弱小的原因很简单
It'd be way too easy to say Stan preys
因为他是个烂人
On the weak simply because he's a dick.
不
No.
不止这些
No, no.
斯坦这个人
Stan here
还不能单用烂人来定义
Is much more complex than that.
依据权威精神科医生所述
See, according to leading psychiatrists
称他为恶霸有以下三个原因
Stan's a bully for one of three reasons.
第一
One
在逞匹夫之勇的外表下
Underneath all of that male bravado
藏着一颗像不安的小女孩般的内心
There's an insecure little girl
使劲儿敲打着密室之门寻求出路
Banging on the closet door trying to get out.
像山顶洞人
Like a caveman
斯坦的脑瓜
stan's brain is
还没发育好呢
underdeveloped.
所以斯坦控制不了自己
Therefore, stan is unable to use selfcontrol.
才表现得咄咄逼人
And so he acts out aggressively.
原因之三
And the third reason.
斯坦那东西很小
Stan has a small wiener.
别伤了自己  大男孩
Don't hurt yourself, big boy.
21岁才能喝酒  谢了
Whoa, whoa, hey. drinking age is still 21, thank you very much.
除非那灵媒给你个假身份  这个只能我喝
Unless your spirit guide gave you a fake id, this is mine.
你吃的什么
What are you eating
不知道  就知道我太饿了
I don't even know. I just know I'm hungry.
老是饿
All the time.
行了  那样吃又不安全又不卫生
Okay, that's not safe or sanitary.
那罐是你的了  做好标记
That's your can now. we'll label it like that.
那么  今天上学都学什么了
So, what did you learn at school today
我是个不称职的老爸  我还以为不错呢
that I'm a bad dad.  I thought it was going great.
对我来说是棒极了
It was going fantastic for me.
然后呢
And then what
然后我发现我儿子
And then I found out my son spent the
在学校的最后一年  被当成受气包耍
Last year being the school punching bag
又眼看我女儿跟个神经质的混蛋舌吻
and watched my daughter get a tongue bath from a psychopathic jackass.
高中很爽  不是吗
High school's delightful, isn't it
是啊  可我觉得我可能选错路了
Yeah. but I think I was wrong about my spirit path.
谁说对了  你看  我跟你说过
And who was right    see    I told you.
我说了不该回高中
I told you high school was the wrong thing.
回高中没错  但不是就篮球而言
High school was right, but it's not about basketball.
是为了帮阿莱克斯和玛姬
It's about helping alex and maggie.
好了  我要走了
All right. I'm getting out of here.
真恶心  孩子们需要他们的老爸
disgusting.  my kids need their father.
干吗呢  好啊  mark
what's going on     oh, hey, mark.
那什么
What was that
三分球啊
A threepointer.
能连续两次都投进吗
Can you do that twice in a row
好  看看给你点压力你怎么样
Okay. let's see you do it with a little pressure.
不错啊  你应该进校队
Wow, you're great. you should be on the team.
你应该加入的  我帮你
You should be on the team. I'm going to get you on the team.
就这样  这样一切就搞定了
That's it. that'll solve everything.
哥们儿  你说啥呢
Dude, what are you talking about
没什么
Nothing.
好开心啊
Well, that was fun.
我都有差不多一个多星期没好好玩了
I haven't been to happy hour in, like, a week and a half.
内奥蜜  谢谢你  我就需要这个
Naomi, thank you so much. that is exactly what I needed.
太好了
Oh, great.
麦克谁  麦克什么啊  没听说过这个人
Mike who     Mike who    I've never heard of the guy.
妈  这是马克  内德叔叔的私生子
Hey, mom, this is mark, uncle ned's bastard.
我知道是有人跟内德叔叔有过孩子
I know. someone had a kid with uncle ned. ew.
你没事吧  奥唐奈太太
You okay, mrs. o'donnell
没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
应该是      女士        孩子  是斯嘉丽女士 别忘了
It's       ms.,       kid. it's       ms.,       scarlet. don't forget that.
对
Oh, right.
你跟我老公长的这么像  是不是
You look just like my husband. doesn't he
我前夫  真是奇怪
My exhusband. that is so weird.
奇怪
It is weird.
怎么回事
What is that
斯嘉丽  过来
Scarlet, I need you to come.
奇怪
Weird.
看见那个没有  看见了
Do you see that     I did see it.
看见他了吗  她不错
You see him     She's nice.
但是看看他
But look at him.
你别再想着这家伙了  往前看
You gotta let that guy go, just out of your brain and move on.
我知道你心里难受  这是自然的
I know you need to grieve a relationship. it's only natural.
好吧
Okay.
你在这儿等着  我去闻闻他
You wait here. I'm going to go smell him.
别  别  亲爱的  你可不能跟青少年玩这个
No, no, no. sweetie. you're not allowed to smell teenagers.
亲爱的  你得听我说  是这样的
Sweetie, you need to hear me on this. here's the thing.
另外  你得明白
The other thing, you need to acknowledge
他跟高中的麦克长的一摸一样
that he looks exactly like mike used to look in high school.
咱们已经说过了  我看见他了
We discussed that. I have looked at him.
你得去认识别人
You need to hook up with someone new.
没错  我值得有人冲我微笑  告诉我我很漂亮
Yeah, I deserve to have somebody smile at me and tell me I'm pretty.
没错  就算是
You do.  Even if it is
叫我跟他一起回家
to just get me to go home with him.
或者吃午饭  对  我们要给你找个新伙伴
Or lunch. but, yes, we're gonna find you a new playmate. ow
你这个小坏蛋
You little turd. you little snot.
是我的错  不好意思  抱歉
My bad. gosh, I'm so sorry.
我看我是有点心不在焉了  因为我在想alex
I guess I was, uh, kind of distracted, as I imagine alex was
听到他妈还不是单身的时候
at hearing about how his mother, who is still married, by the way
准备跟每个有机会认识的男人玩儿
is planning to run around with every guy she can get.
要是在阿富汗
If this is in afghanistan,
她会被砍了手  让山羊拖过街的
She'd be dragged through the streets by goats with her hands cut off.
我只不过说说而已  奈奥蜜
I'm just saying. I'm just saying, naomi.
内奥蜜  管他呢
Naomi.  I don't care.
伙计们
hey, guys. oh.
安静一下  各位坐好
Okay, settle down. everybody take your seats.
谢谢  谢谢  谢谢  斯坦  谢谢你
Thank you, thank you. thank you, stan. thank you.
好的
Okay,
今天我们要继续讨论人类性行为
today we will be continuing our discussion on human sexuality.
就像我们谈论过的
And as we discussed,
学校的官方政策是要禁止
the official school policy is abstinence.
很明智
Now, that is very sensible.
我很高兴这里的人思想都很健康
I'm glad that someone here has their head screwed on straight.
我想我们大家都应该做个禁欲的约定
I think all of us should make a pact to abstain from sex.
现在谁赞成我说的  各位
Now, who's with me, you guys    come on.
天啊
Oh, my god.
玛姬
maggie
不管怎么着  说真的吧
However, let's get real.
我知道要求高中生禁欲
I know asking high school seniors to be abstinent
就好像要求豪猪能拉出羊奶酪一样  恶心
is like asking a porcupine to poop goat cheese. yuck.
由于你们中的大多数人
So since the majority of you are or
在某个时候性行为比较活跃
Will become sexually active at some point
不过那个时期应该是很久以后了  对吧
But that point should be way, way in the future, right
那么  学校官方的立场是
Well, the official school position
我们为你们的安全性行为做了准备
is that we prepare you for safe sex now.
请每人领一个  挨个传下去
So please take one and pass it down.
我需求很大
I have needs.
没必要拿那么多  斯坦  给马克一个
You don't need these. stan, give one to mark.
不  不  他说的对  我不需要
No. no, you know what, he's right. he's right. I don't need one.
知道为啥我不要吗
You know why I don't need one
因为我没爱上任何一个人
because there's no one I'm in love with.
那是      做爱      对吗
It's called       making love,       isn't it
可能我的思想落伍了
Maybe I'm oldfashioned,
但我认为那应该和你爱的人一起做的事
But I think that means you do it with someone you love.
最好是婚后
And preferably when you're married.
当你准备好承担这份爱且寄托于子孙
You know, when you're ready to take that love and turn it into a baby.
那才是爱情的真谛
Because that's what love is.
当你第一刻抱着你的宝贝
It's that first moment when you hold your baby girl
你从没见过这么小而精致的东西
and you didn't know that anything could be so small or so delicate.
你能感受那微弱的心跳
And you feel that tiny heart beat
就知道没有比这个更让你疼爱的了
and you know that you couldn't love anything more in the whole world.
你会希望自己对这个小生命负责
And you hope that you can do right by that little girl
当她摔倒的时候你会在她身边
And always be there to catch her when she falls,
没有什么可以伤害到她
And that nothing ever hurts her.
不会摔坏胳膊
Not a broken arm
不会做恶梦
or a bad dream
也不会伤心
or a broken heart.
我不要了  拿走   我也不要了
I don't want these. just take them.  Me either.
真的啊
Are you serious
好  不错  很好
Great, fine, wonderful.
再给我点儿
More for me.
够我一个礼拜的了
Now I got enough for the whole weekend.
天啊
Oh, my god
斯坦  小伙子们  别打了
stan    boys, stop it
拉开  把他拉走  斯坦
Break it up   get off him, stan
把手机都拿开  别拍了
Put those phones away   stop it
别打了  不许打架
stop hitting him   no fighting
喜欢吗  你会再进监狱的
You like that     You're gonna go to jail again.
看看这个  就像他老妈一样扇他耳光
Look at that. he slapped him like a mother.
真恶心
That thing sucks.
真不怎么样
oh, that's wrong.
看看这个  我纽约的表哥给我发的
Yo, check this out. my cousin in new york sent it to me.
我没来晚吧
I hope I'm not late for our meeting.
因为打架要被降级  真好  谁赢了
Busted for fighting, nice. who won
实际上是打平了
You know, it was actually pretty even.
真的
Really
视频网站上看你是被爆打了一顿
On youtube it looked like you got your ass kicked.
我都看了好几遍了
I saw it a couple times.
你穿的这是什么啊
what are you wearing
贝克汉姆  啥
beckham.  no, what
衣服  对
Oh, the clothes. oh, right.
对于没受过训练的眼睛  我就像个傻逼一样
To the untrained eye, I look like a total idiot.
你就是  真的
You do, in fact.
实际上是诱惑的技术行为  就跟孔雀一样
Ah. but it's actually a seduction technique known as       peacocking.
我的装备是双功能的
My outfit serves the dual function of icebreaker
可以破冰也可以吸引关注
and attentiongetter.
现在进去吧
You can go in now.
看着
Watch.
你是展示自己吗
Are you peacocking
真的吗  你觉得有用吗
Really    you think that's gonna work
我觉得有
I think it just might.
是奥唐奈太太  你好吗
Is that    mrs. o'donnell   how you doing
你好吗
Hello, how are you
我很好  你呢
I'm good. how are you
还好
Good.
我该慢慢适应了
Wow. this is gonna take some getting used to.
你是内德的儿子
You're ned's son
对  内德生了我
Yeah. yeah. ned gave birth to me.
他没生了我  你知道我啥意思
Well, he didn't give birth  you know what I meant.
你还在做园艺
You're doing some gardening.
我重新修整了我的后院
I'm redoing the backyard.
想看看吗
You want to see
当然了  我有空
Yeah, sure. I got some time.
显然我还有好多活要干呢
Yeah. obviously, I still have a lot to do.
你可以把它放在  放在这儿
You can put that   Right here
好吧
All right.
谢谢
Thank you.
那么就这样了  就这样
so this is it.  this is it.
一直就是这样比较糟糕
It used to look a lot worse.
基本上  我是计划在这里放个池塘
Basically, uh, what I planned to do was to put a pond in over here
好  然后放上水
Okay.   and have water
两边流水
streaming in from both sides.
然后再放个大平台在这里
And then put a big deck right here
还有石板露台在这里
and then a flagstone patio there
中间放上草皮
with sod in between.
肯定好看
That would be pretty.
上面再加上
And then to have twinkling lights
闪闪的灯饰
above the whole thing
这样每天晚上就像星空似的
so that every night is a starry one.
一定棒极了  斯嘉
It's gonna be amazing, scar.
你刚叫我什么
What did you just call me
我说  肯定棒极了  你叫我斯嘉
I just said,       lt'll be amazing.        you called me       scar.
只有我老公才那么叫我
My husband's the only one who calls me that.
你要帮忙吗
Could you use some help
我自愿的  又年轻又强壮
Volunteer. I'm young, I'm strong.
好吧  行
Right, got it. okay.
我知道那种酷哥钓女人的事
I realize that whole lady cougar hunting
那种姐弟恋的事
the       mothers I'd like to,       you know, whatever, thing
够你们这些小年轻炫耀的
is big with you guys, right
特别是你们高中生
with you high school boys
但是咱们之间不可能
But that's not gonna happen between me and you.
我也没那意思啊
I didn't even mean it that way.
我倒想的更多的是商业经验
I was thinking more along the lines of business experience,
申请大学之类的
College application.
但是如果你想那样的话
But if you want to go there, that's
我给你把铁锹把  好
so I'll just get you a shovel, then     yeah.
好的
Okay.
怎么了
What
我说咱们能行
I said we could do it
你看见斯坦的表情了吗
Did you see the look on stan's face
阿莱克斯  选拔赛怎么样了
Alex    what happened at the tryouts
还好吗
how'd it go
还好  马克很不错  很棒
It was good. mark had a great tryout. he played great.
对  我也不错  我入选校队了
yeah.  and so did i. I made the team.
真的  太好了  太为你自豪了
Really    oh, great   that's so good. I'm so proud of you.
我也是
Me too.
他干的真的很棒
He did great out there.
马克  那样非常不合适
Oh, mark. that's super inappropriate.
干的真棒
L  good job today.
干的好  谢谢
good job    thanks.
我要给你看点儿东西  过来
I want to show you something. come here. I wanna show you guys.
你挂上灯了  是啊
You hung the lights.  Yes.
我想第一个叫你们看
I wanted you guys to be the first to see.
妈  太酷了  真的
Mom, it's sick.  Really
太好了
It's so good.
老天
Oh, my gosh.
马克  哥们咱们该去练习了
Mark. mark, we should go practice, dude.
周五就比赛了  妈  真不赖
The game's on friday. mom, such a good job.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think
棒极了
It's amazing.
当大家都发现你多有才的时候
When people see how talented you are,
你会是全市有名的园艺设计师的
You'll be designing gardens all over the city.
真的吗
Really
谢谢你  马克  真的谢谢你
Well, thank you, mark. that's nice.
我得走了  晚上有个约会  你有 你有约会
I have to go. I have a date tonight.  you have a     you have a date
我要去跳舞  简直太荒唐了  我跳的很烂
I'm going dancing, which is ridiculous because I'm a terrible dancer.
你跳的很好  什么
you're an amazing dancer.  what
看着你就会跳
You just look like you can move.
好吧
Um, okay.
我要走了  玩的开心  mark
I'm going to go, so have fun, mark.
晚安
Night.
你看什么呢  跳的很棒啊
what are you looking at     that was great.
这是蛇舞
That is the snake.
你1岁的时候这个舞相当火爆
That was a very hot dance when you were 1.
教教我  不行
teach it to me.  I can't.
舞步很难的
It's a very advanced step
我知道你不怎么信  因为看我跳起来很轻松
which I know is hard to believe because I make it look effortless.
这对所有跳舞的人来说都不简单
That's the secret to all great dancers.
叫我试试
Try me.
你干吗要选那首歌
Why did you pick that song
我也不知道  就是  好像它让我挑的
Oh, I don't know. it just, uh, kind of spoke to me.
有意思
Hm. that's funny.
那是我跟我老公在婚礼上跳舞用的曲子
That's the song that my husband and I danced to at our wedding.
很有品位的一个男人
Hm. a man of good taste.
想让我教你怎么跳舞吗  想啊
want me to show you some dance moves     I'd love to.
我是在婚礼上学的
That I learned at my wedding.
不错  对  你就咱在那儿  就那样
great.  yeah. okay, you stand here, like that.
对  就这样  我站在这里
Okay, like that, and I'll stand here.
不对  你就站在那里  就那儿
no, you stand right there.  right there.
好了  准备好没  右脚向后然后左脚向后
Okay, ready    so you go right foot back and then left foot back.
然后右脚快  左  右  左  右
And then quick right, left, right, left, right.
再右脚
And then right  oh.
不错  左  右  左  右
That was good. and left, right, left, right.
不错
That's good.
真的很不错  你学的很快
That was really good. you're picking that up pretty quickly.
你说你老公
So you mentioned your husband.
你觉不觉得你们会和好
Do you think you guys are ever going to get back together
不
Um, no.
干吗这么肯定
Why are you so sure
可能他会去弥补一下
Maybe there's something he could do to fix things.
我爱我老公  我在乎他
I love my husband and care about him
但有时候  这样并不够
but sometimes that just is not enough.
那就是他的错了
Well, he blew it.
跳
Jump.
妈妈  嗯
Mom     Yeah.
阿莱克斯
Hey, Alex.
妈  我是你的妈妈
Mom     I'm your mom.
我是阿莱克斯的妈妈马克
I am Alex's mom, Mark.
当然
Yeah.
你的男伴到了  什么
Your date is here.  Huh
在大门前  你的男伴  好的
The front door. your date.  Okay.
她有点紧张  这有点恐怖对不
She was nervous. it's creepy, right
有点
Little bit.
她不年轻了  就像
She's so old, it's like
你和你所有朋友的妈妈都跳舞吗
Dance with all your friend's moms
常有的事
Pretty much.
你好  斯嘉丽  你好
Oh, hi, Scarlet.  Hello.
你太漂亮了  送你的  哦  谢谢
Wow, you look amazing. here. pour vous.  Oh, thank you.
康乃馨  太过时了吧
Carnations. what a douche bag.
马克
Mark.
没  没事的  真抱歉
No, that's okay.  I'm sorry.
我是个单身父亲
I'm a single dad.
做儿子的看我约他妈妈都会有敌意
It's totally normal for sons to feel weird
这很正常
when their moms date.
我是说  他们也是想代替爸爸保护这个家
I mean, he's stepping into dad's shoes, protecting the castle.
他不是我儿子  但   哦
He's not my son, but   Oh.
那就有点怪了
Then that's weird.
是有点  嗯
It is.  Yeah.
准备走了吗   好
Uh, do you want to go     Yeah.
我去拿外套
Let me get my coat.
拜托   拿着这个
Oh, come on.  Hold these, please.
这男人  你刚太没礼貌了
This guy     You're being rude.
你不要麦克叔叔要他
You're going from uncle Mike to this guy     Shh.
小声点  好吧
Be quiet.  Okay.
拜托 他呆头呆脑的
Do me a favor. shh.  He's a tool.
把这个给内德  叫他交给麦克
Give this to Ned, okay, to give to Mike.
是我们的离婚协议书
it's our divorce papers.
记得提醒他27号一定要出席
And remind him that he needs to be there on the 27th.
好吗  谢谢
Okay    thank you.
你去哪呀
Where are you going
嘉米的派对
Jamie's party.
阿莱克斯
Alex
说真的  我不能来这  真的不行
Yeah, uh, seriously, I can't be here. I really can't be here.
你知道斯坦能对我
Do you know how many dangerous and
做出多少危险的事情吗
Hurtful things Stan could do to me here
你有被人把头按到球堆里吗
You had your head shoved in a ball return
那可不像做按摩
it's not a massage.
你已经是篮球队一员了  这是属于你的派对
You're on the basketball team now. okay    this is your party.
她来了
Okay, okay, there she is.
是妮可  我的天
There's Nicole. Oh, god.
哪个   她就在那
Which one     She's right there.
就是你眼前那个
You're looking at
我这边数第三个你那边第二个
she's my 3, your 2.
别看了  你直视她干嘛  冷静点
Stop it. you're looking right at her.  Calm down.
抱歉  你那是什么
Sorry.  What was that
没事  打嗝而已  你没事打嗝干嘛
Nothing, it was a burp.  Why are you burping
肠胃问题  无视它吧  肠胃问题
I have tummy issues. what    get over it.  Tummy issues
她不会喜欢我的  我是个失败者
She's not going to like me. I'm a loser.
你怎么会是失败者呢  就因为斯坦说你是吗
Why are you a loser    because Stan says you're a loser
你觉得斯坦是完人吗  他根本一无是处
Do you think Stan's a winner    stan's going nowhere.
你看上哪个女孩都是她们三生有幸
Any girl in here would be lucky to have your attention.
你哪里了解女孩子们的心  我怎么会不清楚
What do you know about girls     What do I know about girls
我曾经和校花约过会
I used to date the most beautiful girl in school
但是我没有把握机会留住她
And I let her slip through my fingers.
我现在要帮助你
But I won't let that happen to you.
没错   你说的没错
You're right.You're absolutely right.
我就径直走到她们面前介绍我自己
I'm just going to walk up to her and introduce myself.
明天在学校的时候  也许  还是作罢吧
Tomorrow at school. maybe. probably not.
快去吧
Just go.
美女们  你来了
Hey, girls.  Hey, you came.
你好吗  我很好
How are you     Good.
谢谢  有看到玛姬吗  我四处都找不到她
Thank you, um. have you seen Maggie    I've been looking everywhere.
玛姬不在这
Oh, um, Maggie's not here.
但是  有我在呢
But, um, I am.
而且我真的很高兴你来了
And I'm really, really glad you came.
这是她的生日会  抱歉  我没有给你带礼物
It's her birthday.  I didn't get you a present, I'm sorry.
把你包起来送给我就好了  这个
I'll just have to unwrap you.  Heh, heh. okay.
我因为身体过于柔韧被踢出了拉拉队
I was kicked off the cheerleading squad for being too flexible.
坐下  快坐下
Okay, okay. sit down. just sit down.
如果你们自己都不自重
If you girls don't respect yourselves
别人怎么会尊重你们呢
then how do you expect anyone else to respect you
对不
Right
我不需要你尊重我
Don't respect me.
对  你别尊重我
No, don't respect me.
你记不住我的名字也无妨
You don't even have to remember my name.
这太放荡了  你先说的  荡妇
Wow, that's slutty.  First of all, you slut.
是他们父亲的问题
This is some other dad's problem.
嗯  我觉得你很像我家小狗
And, um, I just want to tell you that you look like my dog.
你说什么  你的头发和我家狗的毛很像  因为
Excuse me     Your hair looks like my dog's hair.Because..
是么   不  我的意思是即亮又柔软
Oh, um   No, it's shiny and soft.
我们喂它添加了亚麻的独特狗粮
We give my dog special food. it's got flax in it.
哦  亚麻
Oh, flax.
它特别可爱  这挺好
She's a sweetheart.  That's sweet.
但她已经死掉了
Well, she died.
你是说我看起来像你家死掉的狗
So I look like your dead dog
我太紧张了  我一直想跟你讲话的
I'm just really nervous, and I've wanted to talk to you for so long.
我在想什么呢     没事的  没事
What am I thinking     Don't worry about it. really.
阿莱克斯  天啊  你知道我叫什么
Alex     Oh, my god, you know my name.
你着火了
You're on fire.
真的     你真的着火了
Really     Literally, you're on fire.
什么
What
身上起火了
Literally on fire.
我晕  是真的  我要走了  再见
Whoa. okay. yeah, I'm gonna get out of here. later.
把那边的钥匙给我
Just hand me those keys right there.
钥匙一直放在那
They're in for the night.
如果里面也烧着了
If the keys are locked in there,
你们就都出不去了
I don't know how I'm going to get you guys out.
节约点氧气
Conserve some oxygen in there.
别瞎叫了  氧气有限
Don't scream, you have a limited amount of oxygen.
她们好漂亮  是吧     这漂亮妞还真多
They're pretty, huh    we got some pretty ladies in here.
你在这啊
Oh, there you are.
你来干嘛  我想跟你聊聊斯坦
what do you want     I just want to talk about Stan.
你为什么会和他约会  你知道的  他是个痞子
Why are you dating him    I mean, you know he is not a nice guy.
他不正常
He's crazy.
别这么说他   你根本不了解他
Hey, don't say that about Stan. you don't even know him.
哦   是的  我真的了解他  比你了解的多
Oh, but I do. I really do. I know him better than you.
我们毕业之后就要同居了
Look, we're moving in together after graduation.
斯坦考进乔治敦大学了
Stan got into Georgetown
你说什么  你说什么
What     What
没  斯坦在停车场找到一份管理工作
No. no. Stan got on the management track at home depot.
还真是好工作
Oh, great.
我会去维斯特伍德社区大学
And I'm going to Westwood community college
以方便我们生活
to be closer to him.
这辈子就他了
He's my forever.
那绝对不可能发生  你说什么
There's no way in hell that's happening.  Excuse me
我说那绝对不可能发生
I said,       there's no way in hell that that is happening.
你认为我能让你赌上你的未来吗
You think I'm gonna let you mortgage your future
你觉得我会让你浪费掉所有的努力
You think I'll let you throw away your hard work
所有的成就
Everything that you've accomplished
就为了一个根本不在乎你的变态吗
For some psychopathic guy who doesn't care about you
我决不准  决不准你再见他
I forbid you. I forbid you to see him anymore.
好吧  你以为你是谁啊
Oh, okay   who the hell do you think you are,
我爸爸吗     天
my father      dude
别想这样就走  你真是个怪胎
Don't walk away from me.  You're a freak.
玛格瑞特・萨拉・奥唐奈
Margaret Sarah O'donnell
进展如何     还真是棒极了
Hey. how'd it go     Fantastic.
你腿怎么了
What's on your leg
我们是勇士  耶  耶
We're the warriors   yeah, yeah
防守是制胜关键
Defense wins the game.
有事吗  觉得你气色不好
What's wrong    you look uncomfortable.
没事
Oh. no.
我只是回想上次我在这的情景
I was just thinking that the last time I was here
我丈夫向我求婚
my husband asked me to marry him.
这意义还真深刻
Tough to compete with that.
落后4分   把球传给高德
Down by 6, get the ball to gold.
喊三声齐乎勇士  一二三
Warriors on three. one, two, three.
勇士
Warriors
斯坦你干吗呢  快上
Stan, what are you doing    let's go.
上  阿莱克斯
Go, Alex   whoo
左路
left side.
回防
pick off   right there
他浪费时间太多了  上啊
he's got too much time. come on
传给mckinley  带入禁区
Get it to Mckinley   get it in   get it
守住
Get him
给我球
Ball
快点  传出来
Come on, outside
奥唐奈  传给高德   快传啊
O'donnell   give the ball to gold   give the ball to gold
不  不  不
No, no, no
我们赢了  你真太厉害了  哦  我
We did it   you were great. oh. ooh. I, um
我全是汗  嗯   不好意思
I'm sweaty. um   Sorry about that.
恭喜   真是太棒了
Congratula  that was awesome.
你跳的真  我看到  我喜欢你的舞蹈
You did a great  I saw the  I liked the dance.
我觉得八月  八月不错
Yeah, so I think August  August will be good.
晚安
All right, uh, have a good night.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
你好  多巧啊
Oh. hi. wow, what are the odds
这次又有何贵干
What's it going to be now
难不成你买了自由女神像给我
did you buy me the statue of liberty
我想约你出去  像个成年人
I'm just going to ask you out, okay    like a grownup.
就是两个朋友一起吃晚餐
Just two friends having dinner.
如果事情有所发展
Then if it turns into anything else,
我们还可以重新来过
We'll cross that bridge when we come to it.
不  晚安
No. good night.
我会给每个学生一台笔记本
I'll buy every student a laptop.
你不想让他们拥有笔记本吗
You would deny the children of laptops
马斯特森小姐  为了孩子   好好  好吧
Miss Masterson, the children.  Okay. okay, fine, fine.
我同意了  但这不是约会
Fine. but this is not a date.
绝不是
No, in no way a date.
我这次同意你
And if I do this,
以后不要举止怪异和送我礼物了
you will stop the inappropriate behavior and gifts.
好  我们开车去吃饭
Yes.  And we'll just drive to this restaurant.
不是乘太空梭过去
We won't fly there in the space shuttle
或者俗气无比的加长豪华车
Or drive in some gaudy, tacky limo.
我们坐你的车好不
No, let's take your car. how about
这边
This way.
内德呼叫驾驶员  任务取消  取消  把车开走
Ned to driver, abort. abort, abort. move it out right now.
我真的搞砸了  她跑过来  我应该吻她的
I totally missed it. she came right up to me, I should've kissed her.
我却傻楞在那
And I froze.
没事的  我再给你制造个机会
Hey, don't worry. I'll get you another chance.
怎么制造  你要怎么做
How    how are you going to do that
在我家举行庆功宴
Victory party at my house
玛姬
Maggie.
Maggie    hey, Maggie.
走开
Go away.
怎么了
Hey, what happened
你要干嘛
What do you want
摸摸我的头说        我说吧
Rub it in my face  say,       I told you so
不  不  我不会的
No. no, I really don't.
到底怎么了
Just tell me what happened.
斯坦把我甩了
Stan dumped me.
斯坦把你甩了
Stan dumped you
斯坦把你甩了  什么
Stan dumped you    what
怎么回事  他怎么说的
What happened    how did this     what did he do
他怎么说的
What did he do
比赛之后
After the game
我们
We
他带我去了后场  我们
He took me behind the quad, and we
我听不下去了   你不是吧
I can't hear this. you didn't.
不是吧小玛  没有
No, Mags.  No.
没有
No.
他就因为这个把我甩了
That's why he dumped me.
小玛啊・
Mags, hey.
没事的
Hey, hey, it's okay.
当你年轻的时候
When you're young,
屁大点事感觉就像世界末日一般
everything feels like the end of the world.
其实不然
It's not.
对
Right.
只是个开始
It's just the beginning.
你可能会遇到几个垃圾
You might have to meet a few more jerks
但是总有一天你会遇到
But one day you're going to meet a boy
待你为掌上明珠的王子
Who treats you the way
就像太阳和你升起降落
Like the sun rises and sets with you.
真的是这样吗
You really think so
当然
I know so.
你真贴心
That's so sweet.
你最好了
You're the sweetest.
谢谢你  没事的
Thank you.  It's okay.
哦   谢谢
Ow. oh.  Thank you.
我  我其实来找你是想
Anyways, I, uh, came over here  I was looking for you.
请你去我的派对  不知你肯不肯赏脸
I wanted to invite you to my party. I don't know if you want to come.
我当然想去  好
Yes. I would love to.  Yeah.
哦  真好  谢谢你
Great. that's exciting.  Thank you
谢谢你  真开心
Thank you.  That's very exciting.
我知道  这太好了
I know, it's great. ha, ha.
晚上见
See you tonight.
地点是马克的家
at mark's house.
太酷了 让我玩玩  不错啊
Hey, that's cool. let me see that. that is nice, man.
别动这些玩具  好吗
Don't touch the toys, okay
我会  尽量不要让自己烧起来
Yeah, I'll, uh, try not to light myself on fire tonight.
我手边会准备灭火器的  哦  那就好
I'll keep a fire extinguisher handy.  Oh, good.
要去外面坐坐吗  当然
Do you want to sit outside     Sure.
酒不错
That's delightful.
怎么了  有什么不对吗
What    what
好吧, 我承认不知怎样才能正常点  的确
Okay, I don't know how to act normal.  Clearly.
这就是我的人生路  并非一帆风顺
It's the story of my life. I'm not smooth.
我只是想给你个好印象
I'm just tryig to impress you, okay
我不是经常来这地方吃饭的人
I'm not the kind of guy who comes to places like this.
我是个书呆子
I'm a dork.
我是那种花1万块
The kind of guy who spends 10 grand
买双塔奇兵里的灰袍甘道夫魔杖的人
on gandalf the grey's quarterstaff from the two towers.
是  那的确有点呆
Yes, that does make you a dork.
尤其当灰袍甘道夫为了友情
Especially since gandalf the grey was only in fellowship.
化身为白袍甘道夫重回双塔
He returns in two towers as gandalf the white.
我那时太难过了 对不起 好吗
I was upset. I'm sorry, okay
我要你证明你是爱我的
I need you to show me that you love me.
那样的话我们就能真正同居了
And that way we can get a place together.
不要说了 听着 不管过去如何 我有新男人了
Stop it. look, whatever. I'm with somebody else now.
你说什么  游戏结束了Stan
What     party's over, Stan.
滚出去
Just get out of here.
谁能让我离开这里
Who's gonna make me leave
你吗
You
你知道我会的  但是你满身酒味
You know I would, but it smells like you've been drinking
所以我打算让警察来处理
So I'm just gonna let the cops do it.
这尼姑归你了
You can have the nun.
她反正也不怎么样
She doesn't put out, anyway.
我改主意了
On second thought
我刚做了一个最疯狂的梦
Oh, I just had the craziest dream.
我回到了17岁
I was 17.
我回到高中时代  真是太可怕了
I was back in high school, and it was terrible.
伤疤
Scar.
伤疤  我没有看到伤疤
Scar    I don't see a scar.
听着  我知道你为何不想我和斯坦在一起
Look, I know why you didn't want me to be with Stan.
因为你喜欢我
It's because you wanted me.
你想玩游戏吗  那我就陪你玩
You want to play games    I can play games.
不不不  我是只饥渴的母狮子
no, no, no.  I'm a hungry lioness
你是只小羚羊
And you're a baby gazelle.
玛姬  不 不要这样  停手
Maggie   no, no, no, maggie, stop this now.
你要知道这样的行为有多么不适当吗
If you only knew how highly inappropriate and dysfunctional this is.
住手  拜托你停下来
Stop it. please stop.
玛姬  我不是你想的那种人
Maggie, I'm not the person that you think I am.
不对  你是  不  我不是
yes, you are.  no, I'm not.
是的  你是好人  和他们不一样
You're right, you're good. you're not like the others.
我和他们不一样  我和他们有很大区别
I'm not like others. I'm very different than the others.
很大区别  事实上  你和我从来没有  永远  永远
So different, in fact, that you and I can never, ever, ever,
永远不能在一起
Ever be together.
别咬了  为什么
stop biting.  why
哦  我的天哪  你在说什么
Oh, my god. what are you saying
你很困惑吗
Are you confused
我相当困惑  是的  超级困惑
I'm very confused, yes. extremely confused.
哦  天哪  我 我 我明白了
Oh, my god. i  i  I get it now.
你的头发已经很整齐了  你还要弄得更显眼
And your hair is always perfectly coiffed, and you have highlights.
你在说什么     我是说
what are you talking about     I mean
伙计  你的牛仔裤太瘦了
Dude, your jeans are really tight.
我不是同性恋
I'm not gay.
我恋爱了  玛姬  我恋爱了
I'm in love, Maggie. I'm in love.
我早就恋爱了
I've been in love.
我17岁的时候就和那个女孩谈恋爱了  玛姬
I've been in love with the same girl since I was 17, Maggie.
她和我们一个学校吗
Does she go to our school
我认识吗     告诉我她叫什么
do I know her    tell me her name.
我想知道她叫什么
I want to know her name.
不要  玛姬  别  好吧
no, Maggie. no.  okay.
你告诉你女朋友最好让他看紧你
You tell your girlfriend she better keep a close eye on you.
上帝啊  我的心肝宝贝
Sweet baby jesus.
谢谢
Thanks.
你的沙拉好吃吗
很好吃  这个芝麻菜很新鲜
恩 你在哪里学的说ELF
从附录学的
那么 去你家还是我家
我们买单
We'll take the check.
我死定了
I'm so dead.
不好意思
Excuse me.
斯嘉丽    斯嘉丽  嗨
Scarlet    Scarlet    Scarlet.  hi.
你在这干什么     你看到阿莱克斯了吗
what are you doing here     you seen Alex
他不接电话
He's not picking up his phone.
阿莱克斯没事  他没事  相信我
Alex is fine. Alex is fine, believe me.
事实上  如果发展顺利
In fact, with the way things are going
今天晚上阿莱克斯就会有个女朋友了
by the end of the night Alex could have a girlfriend.
阿莱克斯有女朋友了     是的  她很棒  很可爱
Alex has a girlfriend     yeah, and she's great. she's cute.
过来  我指给你看  在哪
come on, I'll show you.  where
上楼来  跟我来  我指给你看
Walk up the stairs. walk with me for one sec, I'll show you.
你是怎样得到最新版的光晕(一个游戏）
So how ever did you get the newest version of halo
要过6个月才会出预定版呢
It's not due out for another six months.
这么说吧
Well, let's just say
有个人可以满足我的愿望
I said some things to the makeawish people
但是我并不感到自豪
that I'm not totally proud of.
我要杀了他
I'm going to kill him.
所有人都出去
Everybody, out
不  不 .别动费力所珀里斯医生
Oh, no, no. no   no   no   not dr. Philsopholis.
聚会结束了
This party is over
除非你们准备再留校3个月
Unless you want to spend the next three months in detention,
快离开  马上
leave   now
好吧  我们最好去警告Mark
Okay. we better go warn Mark.
你真的很在乎他  不是吗
You really care about him, don't you
是的  那就好  很好
yeah.  that's nice. that's really nice.
你真的需要一个男性榜样
He really needs a male role model.
他是个好孩子  对
he's a great kid.  mmhm.
你知道  他俩都是
You know, they both are.
我觉得你是个好妈妈
I think you're a great mother.
谢谢
Thank you.
他在阳台上  他现在在那
He's on the balcony. he's right there.
妈妈  .这段时间真的很艰难..
mom     this has been a really tough time
你真的很像这个家庭的一员
and you really feel like part of the family.
你不知道我听到你这么说我有多惊讶
You have no idea how amazing it is to hear you say that.
斯嘉丽
Scarlet.
斯嘉丽   斯嘉丽  我不是马克  知道吗
Scarlet   Scarlet, I'm not Mark, okay
我就是他  是我
I'm him, I'm me.
斯嘉丽  我是你丈夫
Scarlet, I'm your husband.
你能等等吗
will you stop it already
你听我说  我是你孩子的父亲  Scar  让我
If you'd listen to me, I am the father of your children   Scar, let me
别这么叫我  不要这么叫我
Don't call me that. don't call me that
你是一个古怪的家伙
You are a weirdo little manchild
给我两分钟时间让我解释清楚
Give me two seconds, and I can explain this
你是个变态
You are a pervert
走吧  走吧  走吧
Get out, and get out, and get out.
你可以走了
You can leave.
恩  这确实不是我想要的不明不白的关系
Well, this isn't exactly the inconspicuous relationship I wanted.
你现在知道我为什么不约学生家长了吧
I'm sure now you can see why I don't date my students' parents.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
抱歉  我不知道这件事情会难以收场
I'm sorry. I had no idea that it was going to get so out of control.
恩  真的吗
hm. really
很抱歉  我想这是我应得的
now I'm sorry.  I guess I deserved that.
第二个是不由自主的  对不起
The second one was out of line. it was uncalled for. sorry.
你还好吗     我真的很抱歉
Are you okay    I'm really sorry.
3个就扯平了  现在平了
Three makes it even. now we're even.
你怎么样了     你还好吗
How are you    you okay
是的
Yeah.
完成了
And finished.
这块地毯的范围
With the rug area.
但是我们有了很大的进展
But we've made very good progress.
我们得休息一下了
We deserve a break.
我失去了我的家人
I lost my family.
麦克
Hey, Mike
如果这算安慰的话
If it's any consolation,
我想你真的帮到了你的孩子
I think you really did help your kids.
你已经尽职了  现在英雄可以继续向前了
You did your job, and now the hero can move on.
我不想
I don't want to.
也许他们不再需要我了  但是我需要他们
Maybe they don't need me anymore, but I need them.
我不想惹你烦
Hey, not to be a buzzkill
但是你应该去法庭了
but you're due in court
在22分钟内
in 22 minutes.
内德  我需要些时间
Ned, I need more time.
我必须阻止这一切  去开车
I have to stop this.  to the Nedmobile.
等等  内德  内德  怎么了
wait, Ned, Ned, Ned.  yes.
裤子  我应该穿上裤子  是的
pants.  I should have pants on. yes.
快点  格兰
Come on, Glenn
他就是个名字动听爱争吵的侏儒
He's nothing but a glorified midget wrangler.
要不是穿那个背心也不会变得如此高大
You wouldn't be so big without that vest
拿好下面那个东西  抓好了  拉起来
Grab that thing that's down there. grab it. just hold that up.
你从哪弄到的     最多20美分
where you get this     best 20 ever spent.
节省了我半个小时的路程
Saves me a half hour on my commute.
老兄  举起来  把它举起来
Dude, just hold it. hold it way up.
所有的真相  你能像上帝发誓都是事实吗
the whole truth, but the truth, so help you god
我能
I do.
你在加州提起一起离婚诉讼
You request a divorce by the state of california
以性格不合为理由  是吗
citing irreconcilable differences. this correct
是的  法官大人  麦克尔・奥唐奈在场吗
yes, your honor.  is Michael o'donnell present
不  法官大人
No, your honor.
我将他的缺席视为同意离婚
I take his absence as agreement to the orders of the divorce.
你没有申请单方监护吗     没有  法官大人
you are not requesting sole custody     no, your honor.
你不能歪曲事实
you can't handle the truth
什么
What
抱歉  我太着急了
I'm sorry, I panicked.
这是我脑袋冒出的第一句话
it was the first thing that came into my mind.
法官大人
Your majesty.
你是谁     他是我好朋友的丈夫
who are you     that's my husband's best friend.
你是律师  好朋友
You a lawyer, best friend
是的  不
yes.  no.
我相信我口袋里的东西会让法官信服的
I believe the law degree in my pocket says so.
是的  他有点脏
Yes, and it's a little bit smeared
因为我在车里的时候坐在上面
because I sat on it in the car
并不是因为我刚打印出来
not because I printed it out recently.
就算这是真的  你要解释你想做什么吗
Let's pretend that's real. want to explain what you're doing
我们
We
来阻止一场严重的
are stopping a gross
误判
miScarriage ofjustice
那
That
好的  如果你让我解释  我能解释这一切
Okay, if you'd just let me explain. I can explain this.
你过你可以听
If you would just listen
我这有封麦克・奥唐奈的信
I've got a letter from Mike o'donnell,
他是这案子里的丈夫
he's the husband in this case
对不起  我们正在
I'm sorry. we're in the middle
法官大人  如果可以  请让我听听信的内容
Your honor, if it's okay, I'd like to hear the letter, please.
谢谢  法官大人
Thank you, your honor.
这是一封麦克・奥唐奈的信
This is a letter from Mike o'donnell.
他希望我来读
He wanted me to read it.
斯嘉丽
Scarlet
在你进行官司之前
before you go through with this
我希望您能回忆一下1988年9月7日那天
i want to remind you of september 7th, 1988.
那是我第一次见到你
It was the first time that I saw you.
你正在读《比零还少》
You were reading less than zero.
你穿着枪炮玫瑰乐队的T恤
You were wearing a guns n' roses tshirt.
我从没见过这么完美的事物
I'd never seen anything so perfect.
我记得我想的是要么和你在一起  要么去死
I remember thinking that I had to have you, or I'd die.
然后你悄悄对我说你爱上了我
Then you whispered that you loved me
在归国舞会上
at the homecoming dance.
然后我感觉
And I felt
那么平静
so peaceful
那么安全
and safe.
因为我知道从那天起不管发生了什么
Because I knew that no matter what happeNed from that day on
都不会太糟糕
nothing could ever be that bad.
因为我有你
Because I had you.
然后我一步步成长
And then I grew up
我迷失了方向
and I lost my way.
因为我自己的错而责怪你
And I blamed you for my failures.
我知道你今天这么做是逼不得已
And I know that you think you have to do this today.
我并不想让你这么做
I don't want you to.
但是我想
But I guess
如果我还爱你
if I love you
我就应该让你有新的生活
i should let you move on.
好了  孩子  你可以走了
All right, son, you need to go now.
我们继续
Let's proceed.
对不起  法官大人  请问
I'm sorry, your honor. would it be okay
我是否可以将这个案子延期一段时间
if we postpone this for now for just a little while
可以吗
Would that be okay
延期三十天  下一个案子
PostpoNed 30 days. next case.
自从毕业后
Haven't seen you
就从来没看你这么努力的训练过
practice this hard since school.
是的  你知道
Yeah, you know,
如果我想让那些校园侦探记住我
if I want to impress these college scouts
我必须专心训练
then I need to stay focused.
等等  你不是还想拿奖学金吧  是吗
Wait, wait. you're not still trying to get a scholarship, are you
当心  伙计  你不是想放弃精神之路吧
Be careful, man. you do not want to get off of the spirit path.
根本没路  内德  根本没有路  我做不到
There's no path, Ned   there's no path   I can't do it
我只能让事情变得更糟
I just made it worse for them.
我妻子很开心
My wife is happier,
我的消失让所有人都很开心  内德
everyone's happier with me out of the picture, Ned.
该往前看了
It's time to move on.
该走了  妈妈
It's time to go, mom.
高德  为比赛保留点精力了吧  好吗
Hey, gold, save something for the game, huh
只是热热身  教练
Just warming up, coach.
告诉你一个内部消息
Got a little inside info for you.
俄亥俄州立的球探又来了  和教练在一起
The scout from ohio state is back, and the coach is with him.
你打个半场球  我知道你有能力
You play half the game I know you're capable of
明年你能打进大学队  是吗
you're going to be playing college ball next year, huh
是这么计划的  教练  把球给我
that's the plan, coach.  give me the ball.
好了  集合  孩子们  照相了
All right, gather up, jockstraps. picture time.
别把相机弄坏了
Try not to break the camera.
我已经迫不及待要去乔治城
I can't wait to go to georgetown
开始和大学男孩约会了
and start dating college boys.
我想马克会和阿莱克斯一起出来找我
I thought Mark was hanging out with Alex to get to me,
而不是你
not you.
好的  女士们  动起来
All right, ladies, let's bring it in.
简   简
Jane   Jane
简  对不起  对不起
Jane   I'm sorry, sorry.
内德  内德  噢  抱歉
Ned, Ned, Ned.  oh, sorry.
内德  嗨  嗨
Ned. yeah. hi.  hi.
我需要和你谈谈  你在做什么
I need to talk to you.  what are you doing
我练习过这个  呃
I practiced this, uh.
好的
Okay.
我刚才看到我好朋友失去了
I have just seen my best friend lose
对他来说很重要的每一件事情
Everything than means anything to him.
也许我们不该去那  但是
And maybe we'll never be there, but
是的  我明白  但是我告诉过你我是这的校长
Yes, I understand, but I have told you before that I am the principal
是的  而且我不会和
yes.  and I cannot be seen
我学生的家长约会
with my students' parents.
但是  简  为什么你会见到我
But, Jane, how can you be seen with me
我穿隐形衣呢
when I'm wearing the cloak of invisibility
简  我所想的只是一个做朋友的机会
Jane, all I'm asking is a chance for us to be friends.
因为你是唯一一个我想陪在身边的人
Because you're the one I want by my side
当我经历精灵城堡的风暴时
when I'm storming the elvish castle of ganakinesh.
你随时都可以来我的地牢进行抢劫
You can plunder my dungeon anytime.
我会带上我的长弓
I'll bring my long bow.
武士队   加油
Warriors   yeah
加油
Come on.
天哪
Oh, my god.
妈妈  你还好吗
Mom    are you okay
我不能再待在这了  我必须走了
I can't be here again. I have to go.
比赛  那是你的未来  孩子才是我的未来
The game. that's your future. the baby's my future.
你疯了  麦克  不  我不能让你把这些都丢下
That's crazy, Mike. no, I can't let you throw this all away.
再见  Mike
Bye, Mike.
高中明星  从不会让人失望
High school star. never lived up to potential.
你在做什么     我想回到过去
what are you doing    I want to live in the past.
我打赌你希望这些重来一次
I'll bet you wish you had it to do all over again.
你好
Hello
这是个经典时空转移故事
It's a classic transformation story.
灵媒
Spirit guide
你和我  我们在一起了
You and me, we're in this together.
现在轮到你了
It's your turn now.
走步
Traveling.
开球
Green ball
奥唐奈  上场
O'donnell, get in there
斯嘉丽
Scarlet
斯嘉
Scar
斯嘉丽
Scarlet
是你
It is you.
我能解释
I can explain.
你能
You can
不  不是所有的
No, not at all.
你又一次追到我了
you didn't have to come after me again.
是的  因为我爱你
yes, I did, because I love you.
你是我做过的最好的选择  只是我忘记了
You're the best decision I ever made, I just forgot.
然后我就掉下了桥  之后的事情就很奇怪了
And then I fell off a bridge and things got pretty weird after that.
但是我从来没忘记过
But I'm never going to forget again.
听着  我知道我的情绪一直都不好
Look, I know that I've been in a bad mood for the last
持续了20年
20 years.
但是如果你能原谅我  我发誓
But if you let me, I swear,
我会用剩余的时间去弥补你
I will spend the rest of my life making it up to you.
我想我需要人生的第二次机会
I thought I wanted a second chance at life
但是现在我知道我只想和你有第二次机会
but now I know I just want a second chance with y
奇怪
Weird.
是的
Yeah.
我很想你
I missed you.
是的  我要把你放下来因为你变重了
Yeah, I'm gonna put you down because this was a lot easier before.
是的  你有6块腹肌了
Yeah, you did have that sixpack thing going.
我还有机会再看看吗
Is there any chance I'll see that again
我知道你在检查我
I knew you were checking me out.
加油   加油   加油
Go   go   go
成年人能这么做
Adults can have that, though.
好吧  我要开始运动了  也许我可以慢跑回家
Well, I'll work on it. maybe I'll jog home.
内德  嘿
Ned, hey.
我收拾好了所有东西
I packed up all my stuff and I
我想把钥匙还给你  跟你道谢
Wanted to give your key back and say thanks.
哦  不是吧
Hey, whoa. no. no.
没想到在这见到你  masterson校长
Wasn't expecting to see you there, principal masterson.
你看起来真美
You look very pretty.
谢谢
Thank you.
这个力场太强了
The force is strong in this one.
所以我想我会在公司见到你  老板
So I guess I'll be seeing you at work, boss.
是的  奥唐奈教练
Oh, yes, uh, coach o'donnell.
我么很高兴有你的加入
And, um, we are very happy to have you aboard.
伙计  你新工作的第一天我有件礼物给你
Buddy, I got you a little something for your first day at your new job.
不要考虑他值多少钱  他不值钱
Don't think about how much it cost, it's not much.
你给我一个口哨
Hey, you got me a whistle.
别吹
Don't blow it.
好好干
Play big.
你也是
You too.
祝你好运  爱你
Good luck. love you
爱你
Love you